# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

#### Ritesh Kumar Tiwari

Lead Business Development – Supply Chain Management

Flipkart Wholesale B2B Bhagalpur Bihar 812001 Mobile: 9234512120

7004748550

Email: bbbbb1999@gmail.com Tiwari.ritesh@flipkart.com

### **Professional Summary**

A dedicated professional with more than 6.4 Year experience in marketing, Logistic & Warehouse Management service for large scale B2B Marketing industry handling and shipment of goods, transportation of inputs and finished material. I am looking forward to a reputed firm with the approach to take up responsibilities to accomplish organizational goals where in my skills and potentials are being utilized to the maximum; alongside focusing on the scope of enhancing my personal skills & gaining maximum knowledge during my tenure to contribute to the growth of the firm.

### **Career Achievement**

- Logistics Management
- Shipping Management
- Route Planning & Market survey
- Union Management with several Local Bodies
- Manpower Management
- IT Improvement

### **Career Highlights**

• Business Development Executive VI-JOHN INDIA

### **Supply Chain Management From June-2016 to oct 2018**

Business Development - Hiveloop Technology Pvt Ltd. ( Udaan.com )

### Nov 2018 To Nov 2019

. Promoted as Team Leader Nov 2019 to 21 June 2021

- Lead Business Development Flipkart Wholesale 28 June to Till Date
- Responsible for outbound logistics of finished goods in domestics.
- Operations Management (Inbound & Outbound Logistics Transportation, Warehouse/Depot operation)
- Managing the movement of products/equipment/materials in or out of the country in accordance with organizational policy and procedure, and to comply with relevant local and international law and company process.
- Responsible for out bound Dispatch activities FMCG Product.

- Negotiate and manage contracts with suppliers
- Handling customers/Distributor complains.
- Annalise various management information reports viz. monthly reports, compiling of annual statistics, evaluation
- Arrange for correcting / preventive actions to ensure desired customer service levels.
- Coaching and counselling to enhance operational performance.
- Cost optimization and ensuring high level of customer service.
- Handling customers/Distributor complains.
- Develop procedures for coordination of supply chain management with other functional areas, such as sales, marketing, and finance.

# **Academic Qualification**

Qualification	University/Board	Passing year
B.COM	TMBU BHAGALPUR	2010
12th	BIEC PATNA	2006
10 <sup>th</sup>	BSEB PATNA	2004

# **Work Experience**

- Total Work experience of more than 6.4 Year, Worked in VI JOHN INDIA. JUNE 2016- OCT 2018
  - HIVELOOP TECHNOLOGY PVT LTD (UDAAN) NOV 2018 to 21 June 2021 FLIPKART WHOLESALE 28 JUNE 2021 TO Till Date.
- Working as Lead Business Development (TL) in Supply chain management dept. Handling 4 District customer order, dispatches of Fashion Product in more than 68 Lacs every month.
- Working with the Supervision with seller etc. On daily basis.
  Now working in FMCG division and handling Rohini, Old Delhi Mukharjee Nagar Area
- Maintaining the closed relationship with various suppliers, Customers, Sales & Marketing team Etc. to dispatch material on time.

### **Area of Interest**

- Material Dispatches, Logistics and Sales plan management.
- Inventory Management and Warehousing.
- Material procurement and negotiation of contracts.

### **Skills and Strength**

- Billing Software: logic Tally ERP9, Microsoft Office,
- **Personal Traits:** Hard working nature, Good Management skill, Adoptive behavior, Innovative mind.
- **Forte:** Data & statistical analysis, corporate interaction and report writing.

## **Personal Details**

• **DOB**: 25<sup>th</sup> Jan 1989

• Nationality: Indian

• Address: "G N MUKHARJEE ROAD,

Bhikhanpur, -812001(Bihar)

• Language Known: English, Hindi.

• Hobbies: Travelling, Painting, Surfing, Playing (, Pool, Chess, Carrom

Table tennis, etc.) Corporate interaction.

### **Declaration**

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is true to the best of my knowledge.

RITESH KR. TIWARI

Date:

Place: Bhagalpur.

